<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthijs Dam</title>
    <link>https://www.matthijsdam.nl/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matthijs Dam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.matthijsdam.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Penthouse: automatically generate above-the-fold critical CSS</title>
      <link>https://www.matthijsdam.nl/posts/generate-critical-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthijsdam.nl/posts/generate-critical-css/</guid>
      <description>Parsing and generating critical CSS can be a useful technique for improving the performance of your website. Critical CSS refers to the portion of your stylesheets that are necessary for rendering the above-the-fold content of your webpage. By extracting this critical CSS and inlining it into the head of your HTML document, you can ensure that your page is rendered quickly and efficiently.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple example of how to parse and generate critical CSS using penthouse:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.matthijsdam.nl/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthijsdam.nl/projects/</guid>
      <description>OpenPrio Link to heading My first professional client asked me to build a live dashboard for his client MRDH which shows the history and current position of all trams/metros/bus&amp;rsquo;es in the region of The Hague, Rotterdam and Delft.
The front-end reads from the backend using WebSockets.
Tech Stack: JSDoc, Svelte, TailwindCSS, MapLibre Nutrition Glance Link to heading A side project you can discover and learn about nutrition information on Nutrition Glance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🌱</title>
      <link>https://www.matthijsdam.nl/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthijsdam.nl/about/</guid>
      <description>Dedicated to creating modern and intuitive web applications. I have extensive experience with Laravel and Vue.js.
I also have experience with
Typescript Linux Server Engineering DevOps (GitHub Actions/CircleCI) Docker PostgreSQL/MySQL/Redis SEO optimization PHPUnit tests Go (For fast API&amp;rsquo;s) Rust (For fast &amp;amp; simple API&amp;rsquo;s with very clear requirements) And many many more As a vegan I&amp;rsquo;m committed to doing work that helps improve society and our world. I believe that we all have a responsibility to take care of the inhabitants of mother earth, and I strive to use my skills to make a more positive impact.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
